This is an introductory video to the soccer
heart rate dashboard. It is a dashboard which
is used for real-time monitoring of
soccer players during both match and
training scenarios. It focuses on leveraging
heart rate data combined with GPS-data.
Lets first take a look at the training mode.
The training mode has a header with all players
displayed that currently pursue an exercise.
Below the header is the player list, which
displays the actual metrics of each players.
In the header, if a group holds too many players,
such that space becomes an issue, then the groups
will shrink in size to always be able to have an
overview of all present players. To create
a new group just click the new group button,
add a new group name and select
all the players that are in it.
If a group has no players anymore,
then the group can be deleted.
To select a specific player click
on it in the header and it will
be highlighted in the player list.
Looking at the player list, a player is
displayed with their back number, name, and then
their heart rate and GPS-related metrics. All the
way to the left is the metrics name list for more
context. The upper two are heart rate-related,
whereas the ones below are all GPS-related
metrics. This difference is emphasized by
the heart rate-related metrics having a white
background and the GPS-related metrics having
different background colors that can be green,
orange, or red. The actual color stems from
the distance of how far a metric's actual
value is from its corresponding threshold.
The meaning of each color is also indicated by
the color legend at the bottom of the header.
If you want to change the threshold manually,
then click on the settings button on the top
right corner. There you see each threshold per
metric and also have the possibility to select
new metrics or deselect currently displayed ones.
To change a threshold value, click on the current
value, type in the new threshold, and click save.
As you can see the background color of that metric
changed to red, indicating that this metric
already reached its corresponding threshold.
One way to see how much the metric overstepped
the threshold is to click the percentage button
in the top left corner, which displays each
metric's value in percent. Now, if you wanna
see which player of a group is most exhausted,
just click the exhaustion button in the top left,
next to the percentage button, and then
per group, all players will get sorted
according to their overall exhaustion.
Since exercises have a start and an end,
you can specify the start time by clicking
the start button in the top right corner,
and can stop it whenever the exercise is
finished. This has no immediate effect in
the player overview, but can be seen when
analyzing a player in greater detail.
To see more data of player, click on them, and you
will be navigated to the player details view. This
view is split into GPS-related metrics in the top
part, heart-related data in the middle part, and
the session overview graph in the bottom part.
GPS-related metrics show by how much they
overstepped their corresponding threshold, with
a bar and a dashed line indicating the threshold.
Also, the value and its threshold are
shown in the bottom part of the GPS
metric tile. When clicking the plus button,
new metrics can be selected or deselected.
In the middle part, heart rate-related data
is displayed, with a line chart depicting the
heart rate trend. Additionally, the average
speed can be added to analyze the heart rate
trend in greater detail. The chart also displays
three different heart rate zones. On the right,
next to the heart rate zones, are horizontal bar
charts which indicate how much time the player
spent in each zone. Right next to the line chart,
heart rate-related metrics are displayed.
On the Bottom part is a session overview graph
which displays the entire monitoring session with
each exercise highlighted in greater saturation.
On the left, next to the session graph, is the
start and stop button with which an exercise can
be started and stopped the same way as in the
player overview, which was previously shown.
To analyze a certain timespan in more detail,
you can either click on an exercise or use
the sliders to filter a specific timespan.
This will change the GPS-related metrics to show
by how much they grew in the selected period. The
heart zone time bars indicate how much time was
added in the time span, and the heart rate shows
the maximum and minimum of this specific period.
All the way to the bottom are time cut buttons,
which can make the time filtering more efficient.
To switch back to live data, simply click the live
button next to the session graph on the right.
Let's now look at the match mode of the socceHR
dashboard. To navigate there, go back to the
training overview. And click the match mode
icon on the top right. The match mode has
a header that holds buttons with which the
player overview can be manipulated. Below the
header, a soccer field is displayed with each
player being positioned according to their player
position. A player is depicted as a player card,
which holds the three most exhausted GPS
metrics and two heart rate-related metrics.
If more information is needed for a player, just
click the flip button on the top right corner of a
specific player card, and it will grow in size
and hold up to 8 GPS metrics and additionally
display the heart rate trend, heart rate
zone, and one additional heart rate metric.
To view more data for all players, just click the
flip all button in the top left of the header.
Next to the flip all button is again the
percentage button, which was already introduced,
and the repositioning button, which can be
used to change the line-up of the team.
All the way to the left is the substitution
button. Here, specify a player from the
field and a bench player for substitution.
To change the thresholds of a player manually,
again, click the settings button in the top
right. Here, select a player in the header,
then select and deselect metrics on the left
or change thresholds on the right side.
To view a player in greater detail, just click on
a player card, and it will open the player details
view in match mode. The only thing that changes
in relation to the training mode is that there
are no exercises, and hence no start and stop
button for them. Everything else stays the same.